<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-04-13T15:27:19+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Instagram Developer Terms</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2023/2023-01-21-instagram-developer-terms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Instagram Developer Terms" /><published>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2023/2023-01-21-instagram-developer-terms</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2023/2023-01-21-instagram-developer-terms/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="instagram-shortens-the-allowed-inactivity-period-for-developers">Instagram shortens the allowed inactivity period for developers</h1>

<p>Instagram <a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/8382111323ecfa8120c8fcdcad959040fa6cc994">changed</a> the inactivity period for developer accounts, after which it will <strong>suspend or end access</strong> to the platform’s APIs and other functions “with or without notice.” The inactivity period has now been reduced <strong>from 90 to 28 days</strong>.</p>

<p>One of the reasons for the shortening of the allowed inactivity might be due to <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2019/04/25/api-updates/">Meta’s ongoing measures for privacy and security</a>, which include regular re-evaluation of policies and data access. In case of data access expiry due to inactivity, developers are able to <strong>file for an app-review to regain access</strong>.</p>

<p>Instagram’s Graph, Messenger and Basic Display APIs allow users access data for professional and non-professional accounts to reach a wider Instagram audience.</p>]]></content><author><name>Kamila Ilimbayeva</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram shortens the allowed inactivity period for developers]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter Developer Terms</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2023/2023-01-19-twitter-developer-terms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter Developer Terms" /><published>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2023/2023-01-19-twitter-developer-terms</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2023/2023-01-19-twitter-developer-terms/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="twitter-restricts-access-to-some-third-party-tweet-management-tools">Twitter restricts access to some third-party tweet management tools</h1>
<p>Twitter<a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/c74c9d84933b881150d24c0a09776da04c5da111"> introduced</a> an update regarding the use of third-party apps, which are part of its developer terms. Based on the update, Twitter cuts off API (Application Programming Interface) access to third-party apps, which give you the option to scroll your feed and interact.</p>

<p>In the second section of the Developer Terms, Twitter has classified “using or accessing the Licensed Materials to create or attempt to create a substitute or similar service or product to the Twitter Applications” as reverse engineering and other restrictions.</p>

<p>Earlier last week, Twitter informed that it was<a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterDev/status/1615405842735714304"> “enforcing long-standing API rules”</a> and that led to some applications not working. However, they did not explain what rules developers were violating. The developers have been very critical of this decision, which they defined as unprofessional and representing<a href="https://www.macstories.net/stories/twitter-intentionally-ends-third-party-app-developer-access-to-its-apis/#:~:text=Twitter Intentionally Ends Third-Party App Developer Access to Its APIs,-By John Voorhees&amp;text=Late yesterday%2C The Information reported,app access to its APIs."> “an irretrievable breach of trust between it and its developers and users”</a>.</p>

<p>Since Elon Musk’s acquisition of Twitter, the social network’s corporate policies and activities have changed dramatically in several ways. Twitter had also<a href="https://www.socialmediatoday.com/news/twitter-implements-new-rules-banning-links-to-other-social-platforms/639047/"> announced</a> that it would ban all links to other social platforms, with the intention of eliminating free promotion in favour of its competitors. Twitter removed that change due to a large amount of criticism. However, this raises the question of whether Elon Musk does not welcome other platforms using Twitter for their own purposes.</p>

<p>Sources:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.socialmediatoday.com/news/twitter-cuts-off-access-to-some-third-party-tweet-management-tools/640445/"> January 15, 2023. Social Media Today.</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/01/19/twitter-officially-bans-third-party-clients-after-cutting-off-prominent-devs/"> January 20, 2023.Tech Crunch.</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Pablo De la Serna</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter restricts access to some third-party tweet management tools Twitter introduced an update regarding the use of third-party apps, which are part of its developer terms. Based on the update, Twitter cuts off API (Application Programming Interface) access to third-party apps, which give you the option to scroll your feed and interact.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter Community Guidelines</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-15-twitter-community-guidelines/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter Community Guidelines" /><published>2022-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-15-twitter-community-guidelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-15-twitter-community-guidelines/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="twitter-specifies-the-limits-of-location-sharing-and-sets-off-public-debate-about-free-speech">Twitter specifies the limits of location sharing and sets off public debate about free speech</h1>
<p>Just before the end of 2022, Twitter made a change in their<a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/personal-information"> Private information and media policy</a>, providing <a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/d834fc007b6da686ff920ad20bb82f10b0539526">additional information</a> on live location sharing. The update specified the platform’s intention to not only protect private information, but specifically <strong>live</strong> <strong>information and location</strong>.</p>

<p>The company defines live information as “real-time and/or same-day information where there is potential that the individual could still be at the named location”. This could be revelations about someone’s travel route, actual physical location, or “other identifying information that would reveal the person’s location”. Tweets sharing such details will, according to Twitter, be removed <strong>unless it is shared during a crisis situation or in relation to public engagement events</strong>. The policy clarifies that accounts which are specifically dedicated to sharing live locations of other people will be suspended.</p>

<p>Interestingly, this update is connected to a public debate involving Twitter CEO Elon Musk. The platform’s recent owner<a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1603181423787380737"> tweeted</a> about this policy change on the same day, stating “Any account doxxing real-time location info of anyone will be suspended, as it is a physical safety violation”. According to reports by<a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/twitter-roasts-elon-musk-for-posting-his-location-at-the-world-cup_n_639f5090e4b0aeb2ace4e956"> HuffPost</a> and<a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/elon-musk-told-journalists-you-dox-you-get-suspended-on-twitter-spaces-and-then-the-group-chat-feature-went-dark-11671214100"> MarketWatch</a>, <strong>the change of policy caused several journalists from the Washington Post, New York Times and CNN to be suspended from the platform</strong>, as they wrote articles about the now banned account @ElonJet which tracked all the flights Musk travelled with his private jet in 2022, using publicly available data.</p>

<p>Reportedly, this caused BuzzFeed News tech writer Katie Notopoulos to open up a hTwitter space audio discussion about the suspensions. Musk himself joined the Space on the evening of December 15, saying “You dox, you get suspended. End of story. That’s it.” However, the suspended journalists claimed that they just implemented a “routine journalistic practice”. Regarding the public dispute, the Washington post<a href="https://twitter.com/WashPostPR/status/1603592735973425152?s=20&amp;t=y72FTYH9kQFiyIAiyAiAKw"> tweeted</a> that the suspension of its reporter’s account “directly undermines Elon Musk’s claim that he intends to run Twitter as a platform dedicated to free speech.” What is further interesting is that the Private information and media policy does not apply to tweets in which the subject of the media is a public figure. The suspension of the journalists’ accounts is thus debatable. According to<a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-11548409/You-dox-suspended-End-story-Elon-Musk-abruptly-hangs-journalists.html"> Daily Mail</a>, <strong>on January 16, the journalists’ accounts were restored</strong> due to the public backlash Elon Musk received.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lara Müller</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter specifies the limits of location sharing and sets off public debate about free speech Just before the end of 2022, Twitter made a change in their Private information and media policy, providing additional information on live location sharing. The update specified the platform’s intention to not only protect private information, but specifically live information and location.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with giscus comments</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/giscus-comments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with giscus comments" /><published>2022-12-10T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-10T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/giscus-comments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/giscus-comments/"><![CDATA[<p>This post shows how to add GISCUS comments.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts" /><category term="external-services" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with giscus comments]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Youtube Community Guidelines</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-09-youtube-community-guidelines/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Youtube Community Guidelines" /><published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-09-youtube-community-guidelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-09-youtube-community-guidelines/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="youtube-extends-the-criteria-for-age-restricted-content">Youtube extends the criteria for age-restricted content</h1>

<p>Youtube <a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/c24fa29ef2256297b0aa073a6df82f2d8e9a4dce">introduced</a> new criteria regarding the contents that hold age-restriction to its community guidelines. <strong>According to the update, age-restriction can be applied based upon the video titles, video descriptions, live streams, songs, clips etc.</strong></p>

<p>The regulations contained criteria based on only the videos or clips before the update. With these changes, age-restriction can be applied to contents regardless of the videos’ context, since Youtube claims in the <a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2801964?hl=en">policies</a> as follows “This policy applies to videos, video descriptions, comments, live streams, and any other YouTube product or feature.”</p>

<p>Along with the changes in the policy for age-restricted content, the language for the content moderation in the community guidelines has also been transformed to a more comprehensive one. The platform began to use the word “content”, instead of “video” in some cases such as “Use of excessive profanity in the content”.</p>]]></content><author><name>[&quot;…&quot;]</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Youtube extends the criteria for age-restricted content]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitch Privacy Policy</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-02-twitch-privacy-policy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitch Privacy Policy" /><published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-02-twitch-privacy-policy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-12-02-twitch-privacy-policy/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="twitch-enhances-the-treatment-of-user-provided-information">Twitch enhances the treatment of user-provided information</h1>

<p>Twitch has <a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/69f34bdcb4edc037315f12b2f157e117754275fa">elaborated the scope of legal obligations and user data treatment</a>. In particular, the revisited policy states that the users’ agreement to allow the defined treatment of data will be <strong>documented</strong>. It is also now stated that upon registration to the platform and upon interaction with platforms services and features, users provide an <strong>extensive list of personal information</strong>, including voice, image, billing information, address and phone number.</p>

<p>As per the legal obligations: conditions, such as “monitoring and analysing the use of Twitch services,” “investigating and defending ourselves against third-party claims” are now considered by Twitch as <strong>sufficient grounds for documenting users’ consent</strong>. The revisited terms apply to all Twitch Interactive, Inc. applications and services.</p>]]></content><author><name>Kamila Ilimbayeva</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch enhances the treatment of user-provided information]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tiktok Age Limit Streaming</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-10-07-TikTok-Age-Limit-Streaming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tiktok Age Limit Streaming" /><published>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-10-07-TikTok-Age-Limit-Streaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-10-07-TikTok-Age-Limit-Streaming/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="tiktok-raises-the-age-limit-for-hosting-a-live-stream-from-16-to-18">TikTok raises the age limit for hosting a live stream from 16 to 18</h1>

<p>TikTok <a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/6d1406cb8d73b34ff3f1281a04955ea93a097aa6">introduced</a> an update regarding the live stream policies to its community guidelines. **According to the update, the age limit for hosting a live stream is raised from 16 to 18. **From November 23, the account holders must be over 18 years old to be able to host a live stream on TikTok.</p>

<p>In the old version of the regulations, it was indicated that “their content is not eligible to appear in the For You feed (the age thresholds may be higher in some regions).” Accompanied by the update in the <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/community-guidelines#31">Minor Safety regulations</a>, this localized policy has been removed too. TikTok <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/enhancing-the-live-community-experience">reported</a> that the platform is planning to introduce another feature that allows users to only reach an adult audience in their live streams.</p>

<p>The platform shared this update on its blog and said that the platform constantly works for improvements to protect users. Yet, BBC <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-63262102">highlighted</a> that the platform modified the rules after <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-63213567">BBC’s investigation</a> on TikTok profiting from live streams of begging families at Syrian refugee camps.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[TikTok raises the age limit for hosting a live stream from 16 to 18]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tiktok Trackers Policy</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-09-16-Tiktok-Trackers-Policy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tiktok Trackers Policy" /><published>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-09-16-Tiktok-Trackers-Policy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-09-16-Tiktok-Trackers-Policy/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="tiktok-updates-the-list-of-third-party-tracking-companies">TikTok updates the list of third-party tracking companies</h1>

<p>TikTok <a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/c00421c1336b811cf5a0d87336a4aeb8c3e2cbe6">added</a> a new third party for its tracking processes. The company explains the addition by the <strong>importance to improve marketing campaigns, optimize company ad presence and remarket to existing users</strong>.</p>

<p>Previously, <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/legal/tiktok-website-cookies-policy?lang=en">the policy</a> already included tracker pixels (an HTML code that is used for tracking user behavior) of Bing and Facebook, in addition to LinkedIn Insight Tag, Google Analytics, and AppsFlyer – all used for the same purpose, with a duration of 24 months.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://app.urlgeni.us/blog/new-research-across-200-ios-apps-hints-surveillance-marketing-may-still-be-going-strong">recent research</a> of 200 iOS apps, such an addition is yet another contribution to TikTok being the company that uses data tracking and sending it to third parties more than any other social media app.</p>]]></content><author><name>Kamila Ilimbayeva</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[TikTok updates the list of third-party tracking companies]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter Copyright Claims Policy</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-09-06-twitter-copyright-claims-policy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter Copyright Claims Policy" /><published>2022-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-09-06-twitter-copyright-claims-policy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/2022-09-06-twitter-copyright-claims-policy/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="twitter-characterises-cases-of-multiple-copyright-infringements">Twitter characterises cases of multiple copyright infringements</h1>

<p>In the third quarter of 2022, Twitter’s <a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/copyright-policy">Copyright Claims Policy</a> was <a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/e3d40443409007053d0105d25959233d05cdf397%20">supplemented</a> with additional information about accounts with multiple copyright infringements. In the update, the company classified the type of actions that fall under this section.</p>

<p>Multiple copyright infringement include cases in which users re-post material which had already been removed in response to a prior copyright complaint, as well as instances where users (repeatedly) provide access to copyrighted material on third-party websites, and any other cases which suggest that an account seems to solely be used to infringe copyrighted material of others. The consequence for multiple copyright infringements can lead, according to Twitter, to a permanent account suspension. Such permanent bans can be appealed by the respective user.
This update displays the relevance of the general issue of copyright on social media platforms. Most companies are concerned with ways to handle copyright infringements on their online platforms, especially because of the <a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/copyright-legislation">regulatory framework</a> in the European Union which seeks to warrant the protection of authors, performers, artists, and right holders (as stated by the <a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/copyright">European Commission</a>).</p>

<p>This update displays the relevance of the general issue of copyright on social media platforms. Most companies are concerned with ways to handle copyright infringements on their online platforms, especially because of the <a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/copyright-legislation">regulatory framework</a> in the European Union which seeks to warrant the protection of authors, performers, artists, and right holders (as stated by the <a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/copyright">European Commission</a>).</p>]]></content><author><name>Lara Müller</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter characterises cases of multiple copyright infringements]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog" /><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ckatzenbach.github.io/profile-page/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>